hello
uh
my name is gree his name is also green
welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft and we are once again in the
1.14 village and i decided to make this
house a lot bigger it was getting pretty
cramped here with green and myself or
myself and green
green and green
i can totally see it's so weird you can
see that it's a mask and it sits on the
top it is so strange so i decided to
make this house a little bit bigger
because i think i want to make this
a lot taller a lot more dominant i just
need space basically for all the stuff
that i'm going to be working on i'm
going to need some storage space so i
haven't really done anything to the
front of the house but to the rest i
have added on a little bit of the back
but i'm not quite sure where i'm going
to go with that build so i think i'm
going to come back to it a little later
on but a lot has been going on in the
village you see
well over in the distance some sort of
town hall there's a bamboo forest and
lots of other things we already know
iskals there but the big thing is you
can see at the top of the screen there
it says raid
raiders remaining one i haven't
triggered a raid i don't know how this
has happened
there must be one pillager left and they
couldn't find him so i was gonna see if
i could see where he is
i have never done a raid before so i
don't know if i'm making a terrible
mistake but all the villagers seem to be
safe in their houses they've all been
blocked in like false villages in there
impulses villager is in here but they're
all panicking because of that villager
i absolutely
love this
false is home she's made a really cool
camper van i think ren is going to oh
sorry renbob is going to be extremely
jealous of that so let's go and see if
we can find this pillager and see if we
can end this raid because they're all
running around like maniacs also i've
got to say most of the villagers have
vanished so i think one of the first
things we're going to have to do is team
up with mumbo or iskall and try and get
a village breeder a villager breeder to
populate this place again because it's
looking pretty barren
oh there he is
hey little guy
i don't know can he can see me but he
can't hit me is he stuck in there
he really is i don't know why but he's
majorly majorly stuck in this bamboo do
i kill him well in theory he he should
really be firing his crossbow at me so i
don't really know what's going on
hopefully this finishes off the raid
then oh no
did you
i thought the bar had gone
it's
oh no
i may have made a mistake here oh there
they are
there they are
i found them hopefully this isn't too
difficult
oh the ravages hurt the ravages hurt
they hurt a lot they hurt a lot
no
no mistakes mistakes i think i can
handle this i can handle this no one
needs to know what i did
no one needs to know
nobody needs to know nobody needs to
know oh i don't know how you're this is
actually really challenging i don't know
how you're meant to handle this by
yourself there's the guy with the banner
he's running for it
so i got the banner is that it is that
the last thing ominous banner there they
are
oh my goodness there's loads of them
let's crossbow this guy
yes
oh brilliant this is awesome i did run
out of arrows though
oh there's another there's another round
i'm really thankful no one saw this i
didn't actually trigger this raid so i'm
not too worried i'm just cleaning up the
mess
and it turns out that
i raided for a good long while so i've
sped it up an insane amount just so that
you can see
how many pillagers and
vindicators and ravages i had to kill
in order to get through this and
after a while
i started to feel a little bit
suspicious
about how this was going now i've never
done a raid before
but i didn't think that they were
supposed to go on for this long
and i started to think to myself that
something wasn't quite right x is online
x help me someone's starting a raid and
it won't stop and now i understand i
think they started a raid and it just
they left the last guy so that it
wouldn't continue
this is ridiculous
and i think x is just building the town
hall come on look at this
oh my goodness
uh x has just trapped him down there
what is going on
according to x
it's stuck in a raid loop so
i've been killing endless raids for a
long time so we just have to leave this
guy i
i feel like such a fool
such a fool i've been wasting my time
it felt like it because it wasn't
getting stronger and stronger it kept
going stronger then weaker at least
you're safe village agree and that's
what really matters
i've got five of these banners
i think we're gonna have to put these up
on the wall as a trophy
absolutely ridiculous basically if x
hadn't come online and saved me i think
i probably would have continued fighting
those
for about another hour before i realized
something was up i knew something was up
because it was taking so long but i've
never done a raid before so i didn't
know
that is really terrible that it can go
on infinitely i don't even know what to
do with myself now
actually something i've learned from
this is the crossbar i never really got
to use the crossbow in survival before
but i didn't realize you could fire
rockets and i know that scar
has actually created
a crossbow shop now these two things
combined
give me
an idea
because this could be a lot of fun
so i think what we're gonna do is head
over to the shopping district and we're
gonna make a few purchases because i
want to set up a little mini game
judging by the design of this building i
think this might be the crossbow shop
that scar has made i don't know if it's
finished or not but let's go and see if
he's stocking super weapon super weapon
coming soon
and we got some crossbows piercing and
unbreaking that's exactly what i need
actually so i need these crossbows i
could make these myself but i think it's
better to go and actually buy them so
for my little mini game that i want to
do i'm going to need four crossbows
which is
handily exactly what he's got here so 20
diamonds that is very very expensive
scar's done well out of me there it i
what i really needed was rockets but he
hasn't got any so i think i'm gonna have
to make my own rockets unfortunately
but let me explain what the game is
going to be
basically what we're going to do is in
the 114 village i'm going to invite
three other people including myself
and i'm gonna get some nice fireworks in
fact i might have some at my base
so what you can do with rockets is you
can load it into the crossbow and if you
actually you know make the rockets full
you can fire one and then they explode
now the best thing about this is that
they actually do a bit of damage not
only if they hit them but if you hit
the actual explosion
so i don't know if i can do it but if i
was here i would take some damage so how
would i do this i want to be able to
test on myself
no i can't catch up to it myself
finally iskal is here and i can test
what i wanted to test so i've actually
been setting up for a while now because
this game that i've got in my mind has
expanded but i just need to know a few
things i've got all these crossbows and
i've got the setup to have a game of
nerf wars around the village but what i
need to know is how much damage this
does as you can see i've created a
firework with lots of things attached to
it and hopefully
this will do lots of damage so let's see
if i can come here
can i test oh dear
what is that yeah
oh oh it doesn't quite it doesn't one
shot
two
it's a rocket launcher
okay so it takes two hits it you can't
don't think you can do it in one hit
oh that's amazing
oh this is so much fun
okay this could be a lot of fun
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
have a bunch of people in the village
we're all gonna have crossbows with
rocket launches on them we could even
put multi-shot on these and then we've
got to go around and nerf each other
like that
oh my goodness this is going to be so
much fun quake in minecraft that's
basically what this is
do i want in what sort of question is
that
is my house better than yours wait no
[Laughter]
oh that's too much fun
no it's not better than mine it's not
finished yet i've actually done a lot of
progress to my house you can see it's
getting
a lot bigger i've just been extending
and extending adding little bits that go
off to the side on the top overhang
around the back i've done the same
there's just there's so many little bits
to this house now i have a feeling that
this is going to become extraordinarily
tall
it's going to be really fun to make and
i don't really know where i'm going with
it and another thing villager green has
actually been changing profession
i don't know what's going on but he's
now a fisherman it's probably because of
all the barrels around and i moved this
grindstone but he's now a fisherman but
i didn't know the fisherman wore hats so
now he's just got this yellow ring
through him and there's nothing i can do
about it i can get some i get some
bucket of cod from him for three
emeralds what a deal
i think he'll like me more if i buy them
so many fish
so the plan is
we're going to have
four contestants or maybe five
contestants if this cows joining
and i'm going to put these beds
somewhere in the
114 village you won't be allowed to
leave the village and what we'll do
is we'll do something like this where we
have a little respawn area so you got
your bed there you've got your little uh
wool there to show which color team
you're on you have a barrel which will
have the fireworks in them and then
you'll get your crossbow
in theory i really should be making like
four or five crossbows so when you
respawn you can just grab them again
maybe i'll do that have lots of
crossbows along here because i think
it's the fireworks that do damage and
maybe not the piercing i think it's the
explosion that does all the damage i
need to do a bit more testing so we got
the pink one
we've got the white one we got the
yellow one and now just need to place
the cyan one and then i think we've
pretty much got it set up
the village is really starting to come
together all of these haven't changed
but there is a big issue that a lot of
the villagers have vanished so i've got
a plan for that later on that i'll tell
you
if only we could make it so that you
instantly die i mean that would be more
fun so now i've got to spend a little
bit of time prepping this and gathering
all the rockets which is going to take a
long time these are very expensive to
make like you need a lot of dyes a lot
of gunpowder and then i didn't even make
these crossbows i bought them so it may
be that there's only one crossbow not
entirely sure but i'm gonna spend a
little bit of time setting that up so
that we can play the game later on but
there's something else that i want to
show you i've got a shulker box here
full of some very suspect items i've got
cyan terracotta white concrete water
buckets iron
all of these are not blocks that you
would typically see on a house like this
in fact this is the sort of thing that
you might see in a laboratory now this
doesn't look like a laboratory i have
been secretly working
on a secret room
secretly down we go into the basement i
haven't actually finished this yet but
you'll get the idea so down here i've
created a sewer system you might have
seen this concept in a video that i made
recently and so i'm hoping that i can uh
fill this up with water and you have to
crawl through the sewers here and then
if i actually have the water with me
the water here
will then drip over the edge of this and
then it falls out
into here so we've got like a sewage
pipe type thing and then we've got a
room that i've dug out that's going to
be
a laboratory now what we do in this
laboratory you're going to have to find
out in the next episode because there's
obviously still a lot of work to do here
and i don't want to give away all my
secrets to what i'm doing
just in case the other hermits in the
village don't like it i don't want them
to know about my secret laboratory at
all because who knows who knows what
what the hell they may react to this
although iskall can totally see that i'm
down here so for now i'm going to work
on this in secret without anybody
knowing
and we're just going to do our thing and
also i definitely don't have enough
concrete at all so i definitely need a
few hours
maybe
quite a few hours in order just to make
this room look like a laboratory at all
it's just a very much a work in progress
at the moment now that wasn't my fault
you went straight in front of my pickaxe
i don't actually here's a good point i
don't know if you can because you can
swim in the game but can you then swim
into
this pipe because it's crawling
effectively
i mean it's hard to swim up this at all
uh
might take a bit of skill
come on
surely i could get no narrator narrates
all no thank you please don't narrate i
don't know how i did that can you
crafting can you how do i turn the
narrator off
grian says how do i turn the narrator
off that is exactly what i said
iskall85 says no idea neither do i this
is
terrible oh thank goodness okay i sorted
it all right let's see if i can actually
swim up this now that the narrator's not
bothering me this is so strange
it freaks out whenever i try and swim up
this is really challenging trying to get
through oh you can do it you can swim
out
it's it's difficult
and maybe not worth the effort
but you can totally swim back into
the sewer system
oh my goodness i just need to make sure
that wasn't just a fluke and it's
possible to do
this is probably not worth the effort at
all but that is so cool
that is really really cool
so basically all i want to do here is
fill this in
with water to make it seem like a proper
flooded sewer just like this and oh my
goodness
because you're swimming
it actually re it's really quick as well
look at the difference so crawling
through here this is a snail's pace
and this i guess would be like a
ventilation type of crawling but when
you're in the water
you swim really really quickly
that is
that is amazing anyway let's go and
finish
our mini game setup and then let's
invite some hermits on to play this game
oh
my
goodness
so
there's bats everywhere and the
the lighting is all messed up
and mobs are spawning in it this place
you can see it look there's torches here
and it's all messed up
this is really bad
oh no my farm
my farm and my villagers
this update has killed my farm
it's like fake light in here because
look there's there's sea lanterns here
but they're not giving off any light so
all of my crops have died the villagers
have disappeared the light killed all
the crops ladies and gentlemen
1.14 has killed my farms and look at
this
there's just mob spawning galore inside
of this i mean this should still
technically work but the light is a
nuisance i think there's not really a
lot i can do all of the crops are gone
oh this is
this is all finally hit me as well yeah
i think i'm gonna just have to leave
this until we go into a later version i
think this is this is exactly why moving
to that village was a good idea because
i don't have to i don't have to mess
with any of this so let's just grab what
we came for for our little mini game and
pretend like we didn't see anything and
hopefully the next time we come back
here it'll all be fixed
it looks like everything's set up now
all i've got to do is make a few more
crossbows and get them enchanted and
then we'll be ready to play this mini
game it's been very expensive and i
didn't realize quite how expensive this
was going to be
so i may have to charge a diamond entry
just to play
and then there's a prize money after
that or something along those lines but
hopefully now we can invite a bunch of
people and we can play
uh rocket crossbow crossbow rocket
village nerf
it's a work in progress i'll come up
with a name later
hello contestants i'm glad that all of
you have received my invitation to my
very first mini game do you have any
idea what we're going to be doing
nope nope fingers crossed
revolutionary war come on come on
so the fox that delivered invitation did
not give any details no exactly so i'm
glad that you guys have come here i've
transformed the village into a paintball
arena
what we're going to be doing
is a crossbow paintball challenge
where it's a fight to the death using
crossbows and rockets
so maybe i should do a little
demonstration
basically what we've got is crossbows
and some very op fireworks
[Laughter]
so this is what happens it explodes and
it does a lot of damage okay so let me
explain the rules of this game in the
village that i've created a bunch of
different colored stations like this
and in each of these
there are some crossbows so take a look
in the barrel these are your lives
you've got a set of ammunition a
crossbow and then a colored hat you're
not allowed to wear any other items or
have any other items on you and then
you've got to make your way into the
village and shoot the other guys down
and then it's the last man standing and
then you've got three lives does that
make sense wow
yeah if you've never done it before all
you've got to do is hold a firework in
your off hand and then the crossbow in
your main hand and then it should load
it in okay
don't run off yet because you've got to
pay
all right oh yeah of course we do yeah
of course we just got free nobody
mentioned that i'm out i'm out
okay so it's it's one diamond entrance
fee and then two diamonds to the prize
pool and the winner gets the prize pool
i take those for my entrance fee that's
my meager profit for this and then the
winner
gets
10 whole diamonds yay
oh man i want more than i own
well you better try hard then okay are
we ready
yep yep are we ready okay brilliant so
um there's stations around so choose
your color there's red yellow cyan white
and pink yellow oh i'm red i got the
cyan
red that said it today and then i'm
gonna say in the chat i'm gonna count
down to go
all right good luck have fun let's put
the leather cap on and i'm gonna say
three
two
one
go
all right let's load these up
oh here we go
i can see i can see impulse right there
okay so this is like the this
is he
oh okay i'm definitely gonna run out of
ammunition
i don't know if that counts as mine
oh wait no
okay definitely no spawn killing no
spawn killing
the scar just scar's just gone off with
a bang let's go
[Music]
look ow that hurt oh my goodness no
oh that's terrible okay one life down
that was awful i didn't even get anyone
in that all right here we go let's get
back into it
i created these i created these so that
you could get vantage points but this is
not good
oh i just jumped over that one
oh there's one involves
this is manic imagine this with
absolutely everyone on the server where
is he impulse is there he's running away
he's running away i forgot to bring my
carrots where is he oh where did he go
is that
yes yes i got him
oh my goodness this is actually really
this is really scary
let's go
oh i got it direct it direct it
no no
oh i'm so low one hit and i'm out
oh no
oh that didn't go well
all right last life last life i'm on my
last life i i don't know who's still i
don't see you still go oh
impulse
yes yes yes
where is he
huh
oh
let's
no go no
no no
i'm out
i'm out i lost
i was a bit manic i think i got the
scores down so i think
i think impulse went out first
and then it was either me or scar i'm
not sure who
so killed this last place
we came third and fourth
and then iscao and cub fan
came first and second iskal being the
final winner so you grabbed those ten
diamonds you earned them that was a lot
of fun this was a total experiment i had
no idea how good this would be
i personally think we could maybe even
do a bigger game next round
no for sure yeah definitely not less
people this was a lot of fun like rocket
arena in minecraft right so well done
iskall and uh if everyone liked this
then we can uh i can definitely set up
more games but might have to up my
entrance fee because this is expensive
it's an expensive game to do
and with that i think that is the end of
the episode everyone that was a lot of
fun we created a paintball arena in
minecraft in this village this was a
total experiment for my first ever green
game i'm thinking of taking this to the
next level and creating my own minigame
company inside of hermitcraft if you
like this little event then please let
me know in the comments below because i
would love to set up a few more
and get really creative with this thank
you so much for watching everyone as
always i hope you enjoyed this episode
it was a little bit of a different one
and now i've gotta clean up all of this
mess
thank you very much for watching and
good bye
you